What's going on?
We have trouble! There's a Murdergalsh
heading straight for the city!
Say what?!
Are you sure, Rickel?
Yes. This news came straight from
one of the guardsmen.
They said it will reach the south gate
in less than two hours!
What of Zenof?
Captain Zenof and his forces are away on a
monster hunt and won't be back for two days.
Then get in touch with the Adventurer's Guild.
Have them protect the city
and evacuate the citizens.
Hurry!
Right away, milord.
Baron Granvelle. I will help them stave it off.
Hold on, Allen!
The Murdergalsh is nothing to sneeze at!
You're my manservant!
You can't just abandon your post!
If I may, Lady Cecil.
I have one more duty aside from manservant.
I am also the Granvelle family huntsman.
EPISODE 9: THE MURDERGALSH
Run for it! Hurry!
The Murdergalsh is a B-rank monster.
B-RANK
MURDERGALSH, RANBA VILLAGE
200 GOLD COINS
The adventurers in this town
have no shot at beating it.
Unfortunately, I spent all my MP this morning
by using it to farm skill EXP.
MP
C'mon! Recover already!
This way! Move quickly!
Don't let it into the city, no matter what!
Prepare to close the gates!
Please wait!
My wife and daughter are stuck in that carriage!
That's the Murdergalsh?
This is bad!
Get wrecked!
Over here, big lug! I'll chop you down to size!
Are you nuts, kid?!
Run away!
What's wrong? You chicken?
Ugly mutt!
Sweet! That got its attention!
I'm going to lure it towards
the White Dragon Mountains!
Look out! Behind you, kid!
He's making himself bait...
Yer gonna get yerself killed, fool!
MP
Still no MP?!
Oh, hell!
Yikes...
It's playing with me.
MURDERGALSH IS
SMIRKING MISCHIEVOUSLY
What is this, a turn-based RPG?!
Such a creepy-ass monster!
Better not tell Mash about it...
Thank God!
MP
My MP is back at full! Now's my chance!
BEAST E
BIRD E
GRASS E
INSECT E
Delete all copies of Beanzie! And Tama, too!
Then create 34 copies of Papillon!
Gotta pour all my summon buffs
into agility and endurance.
Come get me, sucker!
No worries about being seen
now that I'm away from town.
Go my Papillons! Put it to sleep!
No effect, huh?
Either it has resistance or I'm not doing enough.
All right, summon three more!
Nappy-nap time, you big lug!
That's not good.
Get off my ass already!
I finally shook it off...
Man, why didn't my debuffs work?!
Hopper, Sucker, and Papillon did nothing.
I can't beat that freak
without weakening it somehow!
I had to use up a bunch of my magic stones, too.
But on the plus side,
I led it far away from the city.
Guess I'll head home.
Gimme a freakin' break!
THREE DAYS LATER
Y-young sir!
I made it back...
Allen?!
Oh, hello, milady.
Good morning...
Dummy! How dare a manservant
make me worry so much!
Ah, my deepest apologies.
Mm-hmm. Seems like you're doing just fine.
How much do you remember?
Well... I got chased by the Murdergalsh for
three days. Then I tried to get back to the city.
You'll need to report the details
to the Baron. Can you do that?
Yes.
I see. What a harrowing journey.
I wasn't strong enough to beat the Murdergalsh.
It took everything I had just to lead it away.
My apologies, Baron Granvelle.
Sorry for causing so much trouble.
No need to be sorry, Allen.
We knights are normally the ones
who handle defense of the city.
But you fended the monster off during our absence,
which helped keep casualties to a minimum.
Your courage will be met with reward.
Ten gold coins from the Granvelle family.
And another ten gold coins from the family
who was riding in the carriage that you rescued.
Thank you very much!
Wow! That's the kind of money
I can buy a mithril sword with!
Like winning the lottery, baby!
Be sure not to stray too far from town
in future monster hunts.
Right! I'll be careful!
Glad to hear it.
This mithril sword cuts
like a hot knife through butter!
MITHRIL SWORD
25 GOLD COINS
Hup!
Not enough to pierce through armor, though.
Sweet! Magic stone secured!
Now, then...
Today is all about experimenting.
Hawkins! I need two of you down here!
I want you to fly away for a bit.
Come back here when I call for you!
Then I return one to its card.
Molmo fruits. Jerky. Dried sweet potato.
Put 'em in a row, just like so. Ey!
Plonk.
Pop quiz, Hawkins.
Which of these items is inside of the bag?
Mm-hmm! It should be obvious to you.
BIRD E
But now, let me resummon the Hawkins from earlier.
I want you to tell me
what item is inside of this bag.
But don't just guess randomly.
Figures this one would know, too.
Hey, Hawkins! You can come back now!
Welcome back.
Do you know which item is inside this bag?
Okay, so this one doesn't know.
And now...
Create one Hawkins. And summon!
Do you know what item is inside this bag?
Ah, so even a newly created one
has the same knowledge!
Then how about this?
Summon Poppo!
This one has a high intelligence stat
so it should understand me.
Quiz time, Poppo.
Which of these three items here
is inside of this bag?
You don't know, huh?
In summary...
Summon creatures can synchronize
and update any new information they receive.
However, it's limited to recently summoned
or created copies only.
Already summoned copies
cannot synchronize with each other.
Furthermore, only copies
of the same creature can synchronize.
You guys are always improving
in one way or another, huh?
Not only are you sapient, but your knowledge
is passed down even when one of you dies.
So you're constantly up to date.
As long as the Summoner stays alive,
summon creatures are basically immortal
and have unlimited potential!
ALLEN: AGE 9
EARLY MARCH
Go, Elder Brother! Whip Allen's butt!
This guy is seriously OP!
I'm still losing to him even after farming
a couple thousand C-rank monsters
and reaching level 28!
The duel is over!
Yahoo! Way to go, Elder Brother!
Splendid swordsmanship, Master Mihai.
Your training has really paid off.
Thank you, Zenof.
Yeah...
I've been bested.
I just can't win.
I dunno what they teach at the Academy,
but it must pay dividends
when it comes to EXP for levels and skills!
Thank you, Allen.
You've become quite tough yourself!
It caught me off guard!
Well, I'm still nothing
compared to you, Master Mihai.
Like, for real. I stood
more of a chance last year.
I take comfort in the fact
you're here to protect Cecil.
Learn to do better with a sword, Allen.
Gah, this sucks!
Huh?!
Allen fought the Murdergalsh?!
Well, I'm not sure I'd call it a "fight"...
He ran himself silly for three days and nights!
Then slept like a baby after he came back.
He was in bed for two days straight.
Can you make me sound any worse?
Glad you survived.
Could you have beaten it, Mihai?
No way! B-rank monsters
are too strong for me to take on alone.
At least right now.
Well, then you'll just need to keep training.
Of course, Father!
Baron Granvelle!
Not again...
What's the matter?
The White Dragon has migrated!
Say what?! Are you sure of this?!
The A-rank monster worth 1000 gold coins, eh?
A-RANK
WHITE DRAGON, WHITE DRAGON MOUNTAINS
1000 GOLD COINS
Do you know where the White Dragon has gone?
We received an eyewitness report
from adventurers who said
they saw it leaving its nest
and heading for the Carnel Fiefdom!
My God! So the time has finally come!
It's been ages.
Oh, darling!
If this news is true, then we can go back
to mining mithril after a century of waiting!
Great prosperity will come to our fiefdom!
Zenof! Have the knights take a look at the mines!
If I may, we should start by ascertaining
the location of the dragon's new nest.
Once that's done, I can have my knights
check the status of the four mining sites.
Fair enough.
So, does that mean you'll need to clear out
all the monsters between the city and the mines?
Precisely.
I still have some time off. Want me to help?
Absolutely not, Master Mihai.
It would be disastrous if
the White Dragon returned for some reason.
Not to mention, the base of the mountains are
littered with high-ranked orc and gobin boroughs.
It will take several months
just to access the situation.
I see.
He's right, Mihai.
You should stay focused on your schoolwork.
Of course, Mother.
I look forward to visiting home again next year!
Great.
This is gonna be a problem.
Once the knights start clearing out
the monsters around here,
I'll lose my chance to farm EXP!
I need to formulate a plan!
I'm not gonna miss out!
THE HARDCORE GAMER DOMINATES
IN ANOTHER WORLD WITH GARBAGE BALANCING
Alrighty.
I'm pretty far away from town today
and my MP is at max.
Time to experiment like crazy!
NAME: ALLEN
AGE:
TALENT: SUMMONER
LEVEL:
HP:
MP:
ATTACK:
ENDURANCE:
AGILITY:
INTELLIGENCE:
LUCK:
SKILLS:       SUMMON (5), CREATE (5), FUSE (5)
ENHANCE (5), EXPANSION (4), STORAGE,
SHARE, DELETE, SWORD MASTERY (3), THROW (3)
EXP:
SKILL LEVELS
SUMMON: 5
CREATE: 5    EXP
FUSE: 5     EXP
ENHANCE: 5     EXP
SUMMONS AVAILABLE FOR CREATION:
INSECTS: DEFGH  BEASTS: DEFGH    BIRDS: DEFG    GRASS: DEF
STONES: DE
INVENTORY:
INSECTS E   2 COPIES ,  BEASTS E   14 COPIES ,  BIRDS E   4 COPIES
GRASS E     20 COPIES,    STONES
There's lots to try now
that I'm at Summon level five!
SUMMON 5
And Fuse level five!
FUSE 5
And Expansion level four!
EXPANSION 4
Plus, I even obtained the Share skill!
SHARE
What a freakin' grind.
It took me over two years
just to raise my Summon level by one.
I'm gonna need thirty million EXP
to get to the next level.
Hell Mode is unrelenting as hell.
Let's check out the update to my Expansion skill.
My inventory space is now...
Nice! It increased by another 10,
so I can hold 50 cards!
That means I can get an even bigger stat boost
from my summon buffs!
Next, I've gotta try out this new skill: Share.
SHARE
I hope it's as hype as the Storage skill was!
Based on the name, I'm guessing it lets me share
something with my summon creatures.
Come on out, Hawkins!
Here goes.
Hawkins: Share!
Whoa! What's happening? Is that me?
Am I seeing myself?!
Is this how I look from Hawkins' point of view?
Oh, I get it! I'm sharing his vision!
I can see both my POV and Hawkins' POV.
Let's kick it up a notch.
Hawkins! Fly into the sky!
This is nuts!
I don't believe it. I'm beyond words!
It shares everything that he hears, too.
Can you move for me, Hawkins?
Go right. Now go left.
Awesome! I can control
his movements however I want!
It's almost like I've possessed Hawkins!
Oh, here's an idea.
Hawkins, use Hawk Eye!
Sick! Even his special ability can be shared!
Hawkins is already 50 meters away from me.
That means the Share skill
isn't limited to the summon range.
Man, this is just like multiboxing!
Controlling multiple characters at once
and hogging all the items for yourself.
The most productive
and preferred playstyle of every solo gamer!
It's NOT cheating!
This makes me wonder, how many summon creatures
can I share with at once?
Let's test it out.
Summon three more copies of Hawkins!
Share!
Wow! I can see five POVs now including my own.
This is more like parallel processing
than multi-tasking.
I don't have any more copies
of Hawkins to summon, so...
Tama, I choose you!
Tama: Share!
Sweet! I can use Share on different summons!
Now I'm sharing with five of them
at the same time.
Okay, let's add one more.
Tama: Share!
Agh! M-m-m-my head is killing me!
C-cancel sharing!
Whew. Felt like my head was gonna explode.
Using it with six summons caused me actual pain.
So, maybe sharing with five of them is the max?
Share doesn't have a skill level
associated with it, just like Storage.
It's reasonable to assume five is the limit,
since I can't level it up.
But that seems weird given that I'm able
to summon up to 50 creatures now.
Maybe there's some sort of stat requirement...
INTELLIGENCE:
Oh, I bet it's Intelligence!
With all my buffs,
I'm currently at 1,111 intelligence.
I'm guessing that I can share with
an extra summon for every 200 that I have.
Let's go!
I was planning to create and play around with
my newly unlocked D-rank summons all at once,
but right now I need to boost my intelligence.
Create summon creature Bird D: Hollow!
BIRD D
BUFFS: AGILITY +20, INTELLIGENCE +20
Now create six more.
BIRD D
INTELLEGENCE
Boom, baby! That put my Intelligence over 1,200.
Let's try again: Share!
It worked! I can share with up to six summons now!
So, my Intelligence stat was the key.
Now I know what the devs had in mind
when they gave Summoner such high intelligence.
I wanna try using this skill
with my new summon creatures.
BIRD D
First, create the remaining
five D-rank summon creatures!
INSECT D
BEAST D
STONE D
GRASS D
FISH D
Now summon them!
Wow! So, these are the D-ranks, huh?
With the exception of Tatertot,
they all start with over 100 intelligence,
so they should understand me!
Hmm. Since I can use Share
and order them around...
isn't it feasible for me to hunt monsters
using nothing but my summons now?!
Let's try it and see!
Target sighted!
Spidey! Use Spider Silk!
Teddy! Use Crush!
Bron! Use Protect!
Fillet! Use Spray!
That gave a buff!
And it works on all my creatures!
Go kick ass, team!
Awesome. They totally cleaned house.
They're not one-shotting anything yet,
but Teddy's attack and Spidey's debuff
make pretty short work of C-rank monsters.
Tatertot's ability probably
recovers MP based on its name.
Let me use up my remaining MP
on farming skill EXP.
MP:
Tatertot, use your ability! Crop of Magic!
I got back 1,000 MP! Hell yeah!
Finally an MP recovery item!
I still haven't tested
Hollow's ability, Night Vision.
But it's obviously the opposite of Hawkins.
It should help me scout enemies at night.
Which means...
my telecommand creature squadron
is ready for action!
DAY
NIGHT
Hawkins and Hollow will scout for monsters.
Fillet will buff everyone's evasion rate.
Then Spidey will cripple the enemy
while Teddy attacks them.
I can farm EXP every day of the month
using nothing but my summon creatures!
Talk about perfect!
Fillet's buffs will boost
my Intelligence stat to 1,600.
So I can use Share with eight summons, easy peasy!
Okay, team! Let's go monster hunting!
Be careful to avoid all human adventurers.
Don't attack them, even if they attack you.
Are we clear?
This new skill gives me so much more to do.
Although it makes me feel kinda monstrous.
The White Dragon is just beyond
that mountain range, huh?
I just had a great idea.
There's one more way I can use the Share skill!
My name is Krena the Fierce!
Dogora the Axe User! I challenge you!
A'ight! Bring it!
Next! You're up, Mash!
Okay!
Never see birds like that around here.
Okay, Myulla. Settle down.
There. All done.
Thank you, mommy!
A gold coin...?
Happy to see the fam's doing well.
I'll send you guys more every month.